Before we start creating our content provider,
it's time to go back to our weather
contract. We're going to use the weather contract,
for both database definitions and content provider definitions.
These are the URIs that our contract will expose for a data and view. Some of
them return a list or directory of items.
And some of them return as single item.
The first part of the URI is the content authority which is how the system
disambiguate URIs from different application, similar to the
relationship between a domain name and its website.
A convenient string to use for the content
authority is the package name of the app.
Let's return to our weather contract. We'll add
the CONTENT_AUTHORITY and the BASE_CONTENT_URI for our content
provider to the beginning of our weather
contract. Next, we'll add strings to the base
path of our URIs. Each URI essentially points
to a different table. For each of our
tables, location entry, and weather entry, we
create a content URI that represents the base location for each table. Now,
we'll add some magical value to the location and weather entry contracts.
These contain special MIME type prefixes that indicate that
the URI either returns a directory, list of items,
or a single item. Now, we're going to add some
URI builders and decoder functions in weather entry. It's
convenient to have this as it makes fewer places
in your code aware of the actual URI encoding,
keeping this knowledge in the contract. If you're just
going to have a URI with a standard integer
primary key, which is a typical way of distinguishing between
a query for item or the query for a list
of items, one can use the content URIs with appended
id function. Strings, such as a location setting, can be
appended with the append path function. We can also these
functions to add potentially useful query parameters. In this case,
we use a query parameter for the start date. Query
parameters are useful for when we have a fixed database
query that we want to have some limited parameterization
for. In this case, it will be a parameter for
our join between the two tables. Finally, we have
this function that builds a two part URI that contains
both location and date segments. Below this, we have
helper functions that help decode the URI structure. This hides
the URI structure form our code as well and
places all the knowledge in one place within the contract.